恩佐，首先非常感谢你。
Well Enzo, first thank you very much.
Bueno Enzo, primero muchas gracias.
祝贺这个周年纪念日，成为世界冠军两周年。
Congratulations on this anniversary, two years as world champion.
Felicitaciones por este aniversario, dos años como campeón del mundo.
我要问你这个问题，但我想要我想要
I'm going to ask you the question but I want I want
te voy a hacer la pregunta pero quiero quiero
我想问你关于你现在生活的这一刻......
I want to ask you about this moment you are living with...
quiero preguntarte sobre este momento que están viviendo con...
与切尔西。
with Chelsea.
con el Chelsea.
上个赛季就已经有预兆了，他们上个赛季的表现非常好，但这确实是一个预兆。
Already last season there was like an omen, they had finished very well last season, but this really
Ya en la temporada pasada había como un presagio, habían terminado muy bien la temporada pasada, pero esto realmente
我认为这让每个人都感到惊讶。
I think it's surprising everyone.
creo que está sorprendiendo a todo el mundo.
你是怎么生活的？
How do you live it?
¿Cómo lo viven ustedes?
事实是，是的，当我们在集体层面经历的那一刻，事实是我非常高兴，因为……
The truth is, yes, the moment we are experiencing at a group level, the truth is that I am very happy because...
La verdad que sí, el momento que estamos viviendo a nivel grupal, la verdad que muy feliz porque...
我们每天都努力实现我们的目标，每个周末都能够展示
We work every day to achieve our goals and every weekend to be able to demonstrate
Trabajamos cada día para lograr nuestros objetivos y cada fin de semana poder demostrar
我们正在为伟大的事情做好准备，所以我为团队感到非常高兴。
We are up for great things, so I am very happy for the team.
que estamos para grandes cosas, así que muy feliz por el equipo.
当赛季开始时...
When the season started...
Cuando arrancó la temporada...
事实上，我认为预测中的任何人都不是前三名或冠军争夺者。
In reality, I don't think that anyone in the predictions was not in that top 3 or as contenders for the title.
en la realidad no creo que nadie en los pronósticos ustedes no estaban en ese top 3 o como aspirantes al título.
但现在，所有人都看好这支切尔西。
But now, everyone sees this Chelsea favorably.
Pero ahora sí, ya todo mundo lo ve con buenos ojos a este Chelsea.
你如何看待这一刻？
How do you take this moment?
¿Cómo lo toman ustedes este momento?
是的，显然，正如我告诉你的，我们确实并努力......
Yes, obviously, as I told you, we do and work to...
Sí, obviamente, como te dije, hacemos y trabajamos para...
对于切尔西来说，我们努力让每个人在任何时候都发挥出最好的水平。
For Chelsea we try to give everyone their best at all times.
Para Chelsea tratamos de cada uno dar lo mejor siempre.
团队非常团结。
The team is very united.
El equipo está muy unido.
我的队友们在每次训练中都竭尽全力，事实是……
My teammates give their best in every training session, the truth is...
Mis compañeros en cada entrenamiento dan lo mejor, la verdad que...
没什么，让我们希望继续这一刻，始终谦虚地工作，每个周末......
Nothing, let's hope to continue for this moment always working with humility and every weekend...
Que nada, esperemos seguir por este momento siempre trabajando con humildad y cada fin de semana...
能够展示我们在一周内所做的所有工作以及教练对我们的要求。
being able to demonstrate all the work we do during the week and what the coach asks of us.
poder demostrar de todo el trabajo que hacemos en la semana y los que nos pide el entrenador.
有时当事情没有进展时你会想
Sometimes when things didn't work out you thought
alguna vez cuando las cosas no salían pensabas
假设要达到这一刻是非常困难的。
and let's say that it was going to be very difficult to get to this moment or.
y que digamos que iba a ser muy difícil llegar a este momento o.
我说因为你年轻，但是你虽然年轻，但经验却很丰富，对吧？
I say because of your youth, but despite your youth, you have a lot of experience, right?
digo por tu juventud, pero a pesar de tu juventud, tienes mucha experiencia, ¿no?
所以。
So.
Entonces.
你知道你可以带着你拥有的装备出去吗？
Did you know you could go out with the equipment you had?
¿Sabías que podías salir con el equipo que tenías?
是的，是的，显然。
Yes, yes, obviously.
Sí, sí, obviamente.
我想我们曾经...
I think we had...
Creo que tuvimos...
经过挫折，我们并没有以最好的方式或预期那样开始，但我认为......
Through a setback we didn't start in the best way or as expected, but I think...
a través de un traspié no arrancamos de la mejor manera o como se esperaba, pero creo que...
这支球队非常镇定、非常坚强。
The team held its head very well, very strong.
El equipo se mantuvo muy bien de cabeza, muy fuerte.
每天我们也在理解教练的想法，我想最终今天就结束了
and every day we were also understanding our coach's idea and I think that in the end today it ended
y cada día también íbamos entendiendo la idea de nuestro entrenador y creo que al final hoy en día acabó
我们做得很好，我对此感到非常高兴。
We are doing very well and I am very happy about that.
La estamos llevando muy bien y estoy muy feliz por eso.
我知道这个团队会做出回应，今天......
I knew this team was going to respond and today...
Sabía que este equipo iba a responder y hoy en día...
能够参加冠军争夺战确实非常重要。
Being able to be up there for the title fight is really very important.
Poder estar ahí arriba por la pelea del título la verdad que es muy importante.
您认为恩佐·马雷斯卡对切尔西新闻的关键是什么？
What do you think has been Enzo Maresca's key to this Chelsea news?
¿Cuál crees tú que ha sido la clave de Enzo Maresca para esta actualidad de Chelsea?
嗯，我认为从一开始他就对我们很清楚。
Well, I think from the beginning he was very clear with us.
Bueno, creo que desde un principio él fue muy claro con nosotros.
在这里，发挥作用的不是那些有名字的人，而是那些工作最多、做得最多的人。
Here it is not the one who has a name that is going to play, but rather the one who works the most, the one who is doing the most.
Acá no va a jugar el que tenga nombre, sino el que más trabaje, el que más esté bien.
这句话所表达的道理从一开始就很明确。
The truth that expressed that was very clear from the beginning.
La verdad que plasmó eso fue muy claro desde un principio.
我想所有的孩子都完全理解了。
I think all the kids understood it perfectly.
Creo que todos los chicos lo entendieron a la perfección.
现在，每个周末轮到我们玩的时候，它显然都会崩溃。
and nowadays it obviously collapses every weekend when it's our turn to play.
y hoy en día se desplamado obviamente en cada fin de semana cuando nos toca jugar.
甚至在Conferen上，我们现在已经赢得了小组赛的全部六场比赛。
or even in Conferen, where we have now managed to win all six games in the group stage.
o mismamente en Conferen, que ahora hemos logrado ganar los seis partidos de la fase de grupos.
就你个人而言，恩佐，我想问你，因为在过去的七场比赛中你有7次助攻，3个进球。
You personally, Enzo, I wanted to ask you, because in the last seven games you have seven assists, three goals.
Tu en lo personal, Enzo, te quería preguntar, porque tienes en los últimos siete partidos, siete asistencias, tres goles.
自从你来到切尔西以来，你正处于最好的时刻吗？
Are you in the best moment since your arrival at Chelsea?
¿Estás en el mejor momento desde tu llegada a Chelsea?
嗯，很多人问我同样的事情，我认为在个人层面上是的，因为事实是我一直感觉很好。
Well, many ask me the same thing, I think on a personal level yes, because the truth is that I have been feeling very good.
Bueno, muchos me preguntan lo mismo, creo que a nivel personal sí, porque la verdad es que me vengo sintiendo muy bien.
身体方面，就像足球一样，事实是，这段时间我已经找到了自己的状态
Physically, like football, the truth is that in this time I have managed to find my form
Físicamente, como futbolísticamente, la verdad que en este tiempo he logrado encontrar mi forma
没什么，显然，我非常感谢一直给我信心的队友，也感谢也信任我的教练组。
And nothing, obviously that, I am very grateful to my teammates who always give me confidence, to the coaching staff who also trust me.
Y nada, obviamente eso, agradezco mucho a mis compañeros que siempre me dan la confianza, al cuerpo técnico también que confía en mí.
今天我处于这个时刻，我希望继续这样，能够帮助球队，能够帮助切尔西，并始终尽我所能。
that today I am in this present and I hope to continue like this, to be able to help the team, to be able to help Chelsea and always give my best.
que hoy en día esté en este presente y espero seguir así, poder ayudar al equipo, poder ayudar a Chelsea y siempre dar lo mejor de mí.
你如何看待冠军？
How do you see the championship?
¿Cómo ves en el campeonato?
因为现在看来利物浦已经醒了。
Because now it seemed that Liverpool had already woken up.
Porque ahora parecía que el Liverpool ya se había despertado.
已经被砍了，现在一切都很平衡了，有些球队也回来了
It had already been cut, now everything is very even, some teams are also coming back
ya se había cortado, ahora está todo muy parejo, vienen atrás también algunos equipos
你怎么看？
How do you see?
¿Cómo ves?
因为现在正在玩，几乎没有休息时间，就在玩……
Because now it is being played, there is almost no rest time, it is played...
Porque ahora se está jugando, casi no hay tiempo de descanso, se juega...
几乎每两三天一次。
practically every two or three days.
prácticamente cada dos o tres días.
是的，确实如此，正如我之前所说。
Yes, really, as I said before.
Sí, la verdad, como dije antes.
路很长很远。
The long road is very far away.
El camino largo falta muchísimo.
明显地...
Obviously...
Obviamente...
正如我所说，对我们来说，重要的是要在那里，不要迷失方向。
For us, as I said, it is important to be there and not lose track.
Para nosotros, como dije, es importante estar ahí y no perder pisada.
我们知道利物浦也是一家伟大的俱乐部，它拥有一支非常优秀的球队并且做得很好，但我们也是。
We know that Liverpool is also a great club, that it has a very good squad and is doing things very well, but so are we.
Sabemos que Liverpool también es un gran club, que tiene muy buen plantel y está haciendo las cosas muy bien, pero nosotros también.
我们有武器，我们沿着一条线，我们沿着一条路，让我们希望最终......
We have our weapons, we follow a line, we follow a path and let's hope that in the end...
Tenemos nuestras armas, seguimos una línea, seguimos un camino y esperemos que al final...
成为我们想要的奖励。
be the reward that we want.
sea la recompensa que nosotros queramos.
我想问你的是，本周有很多关于卡塔尔冠军两年的讨论。
I wanted to ask you about, there has been a lot of talk this week about the two years of the Qatar title.
Te quería preguntar sobre, se ha hablado mucho esta semana por los dos años del título de Qatar.
你吸收它，你日复一日地享受它，现在已经庆祝了这两年，我想这很好......
You assimilate it, you enjoy it day by day, now that those two years have been celebrated, I imagine it's good...
lo asimilás, lo disfrutás día con día, ahora que se celebraron esos dos años me imagino que bueno...
那一刻的记忆更加深刻。
That moment comes much more to mind.
que viene mucho más a la mente ese momento.
事实是，是的，我很享受每一天。
The truth is, yes, I enjoy every day.
La verdad que sí, disfruto cada día.
成为世界冠军并不容易。
Being world champion is not easy at all.
Ser campeón del mundo no es nada fácil.
事实是，所取得的成就是......
The truth is what was achieved with...
La verdad lo que se logró con...
与阿根廷队的比赛真是不可思议，我会很享受的。
with Argentina it was incredible and I am going to enjoy it.
con Argentina fue increíble y lo voy a disfrutar.
从我成为冠军的那一刻起直到我去世，我生命中的每一天我都会享受它。
From the moment I became champion until I die, every day of my life I am going to enjoy it.
Desde que salí campeón hasta que me muera, cada día de mi vida voy a disfrutarlo.
因为在足球层面，在世界层面，我认为......
because at the football level, at the world level, I think...
porque a nivel fútbol, a nivel mundial, creo que...
对于一名足球运动员来说，这是最伟大的事情，显然他非常享受这一切。
The greatest thing that can happen to a soccer player and obviously he enjoys it to the fullest.
lo mayor que le puede pasar a un jugador de fútbol y obviamente que lo disfruta al máximo.
有那么一刻，你知道我总是说，当有一天我必须和你说话时，我会把它呈现给你。
There is a moment that you know that I always said, when one day I have to talk to you, I will present it to you.
Hay un momento que sabes que yo siempre dije cuando algún día me toque hablar con vos te lo voy a presentar
迪布封面后的最后一部戏你看了吗？
Did you see the last play after the Dibu cover?
¿viste la última jugada después de la tapada del Dibu?
劳塔罗头球攻入的中锋，如果你还剩下的话……
The center that Lautaro heads in, if you had it left...
El centro que cabecea Lautaro, si te quedaba vos...
这就是目标，这个目标将奉献你。
It was the goal, it was the goal that was going to consecrate you.
Era el gol, era el gol que te iba a consagrar.
你想过这个问题，你也和劳塔罗谈过这个问题。
You have thought about it, you have talked about it with Lautaro.
Lo has pensado, lo has hablado con Lautaro.
是的，我记得那场戏。
Yes, I remember that play.
Sí, me acuerdo de esa jugada.
显然在比赛中我对他大喊让她通过，但是嘿，公牛9号。
Obviously in the game I yelled at him to let her pass, but hey, Bull 9.
Obviamente en el partido le grité que la deje pasar, pero bueno, el Toro 9.
这闻起来像一个目标，他相信
It smells like a goal and he believed that
huele de gol y él creyó que
这可能是一个机会，或者我完全接受我的决定，就是这样，我们是冠军，这是最重要的。
That it could be an opportunity or I totally accept what I have decided, that's it, we are champions, that is the most important thing.
Que pueda ser una oportunidad o acepto totalmente lo que haya decidido, ya está, somos campeones, eso es lo más importante.
后来留不留，我都不在乎了。
Afterwards whether I stayed or not, I don't really care.
después si me he quedado o no, no me importa la verdad.
所以没什么，很开心。
So nothing, very happy.
Así que nada, muy feliz.
为阿根廷队赢得了人们梦寐以求的冠军头衔，我们也是如此。
for having achieved that title with Argentina that people dreamed of so much and so did we.
por haber logrado ese título con Argentina que la gente tanto soñaba y nosotros también.
事实上，这是一种非常巨大的自豪感。
The truth is that a very great pride.
La verdad que un orgullo muy grande.
很难保持冷静，我不知道真相，因为当你看到那些图像时你会变得情绪化，我无法想象你是如何经历的。
It's difficult to stay calm, I don't know the truth, because when you see those images you get emotional, I can't imagine how you experience it.
Difícil mantener la calma, no sé la verdad, porque uno cuando ve esas imágenes se emociona, no me imagino cómo lo viven ustedes.
是的，是的，显然。
Yes, yes, obviously.
Sí, sí, obviamente.
显然，每个视频、每个图像总是带回一段非常美好的回忆……
Each video, each image, obviously, always brings back a very nice memory that...
Cada video, cada imagen, obviamente, siempre trae un recuerdo muy bonito que...
它活在我们心中，事实是，记住那些时刻总是很美好的。
that lives in our hearts and the truth is that it is always nice to remember those moments.
que vive en nuestros corazones y la verdad que siempre es lindo recordar esos momentos.
最后一件事是，我们正处于这样一个时刻：大多数人都可以
The last thing is that we are in a moment where the majority of people who can
La última es que estamos en un momento donde la mayoría de la gente que puede
他与他的家人分享，但你却充满活力，正处于这个甜蜜的时刻。
He shares with his family, but you are in full activity and you are in this sweet moment.
comparte con su familia, pero ustedes están en plena actividad y están en este momento dulce.
你如何度过圣诞节，你和谁一起度过，你的家人到达。
how you spend Christmas, who you spend it with, your family arrives.
cómo pasas la Navidad, con quién lo pasas, llega tu familia.
告诉我一些关于这些重要日期的信息，特别是对于我们拉丁美洲的人来说。
Tell me a little about these important dates, especially for us in Latin America.
Cuéntame un poco de estas fechas tan importantes, sobre todo para nosotros en América Latina.
你是怎么生活的？
How do you live it?
¿Cómo lo vives tú?
是的，是的，是的。
Yes, yes, yes.
Sí, sí, sí.
好吧，我们现在必须在周日比赛，然后我们必须在周五再次比赛。
Well, here we have to play now on Sunday, then we have to play again on Friday.
Bueno, acá nos toca jugar ahora el domingo, después nos toca volver a jugar viernes de nuevo.
事实上，这个日历非常合适。
The truth is that the calendar is very appropriate.
La verdad que el calendario es muy apropiado.
紧的
tight
apretado
但显然还有圣诞节的时间，你必须享受它。
But obviously there is time for Christmas, you have to enjoy it.
Pero obviamente hay tiempo para la Navidad, hay que disfrutar.
我要和我的父母一起度过，事实是......
I'm going to spend it with my parents, the truth is...
La voy a pasar con mis padres, la verdad que...
我很高兴你来看我，我显然会喜欢圣诞节，这对我们来说非常重要。
I am very happy that you have come to see me and I will obviously enjoy Christmas, which for us is very important.
que muy feliz que hayan venido a verme y nada disfrutaré obviamente la navidad que para nosotros es muy importante
最后一个，因为在阿根廷，现在是夏天，但你却冷得要死。
And the last one, because in Argentina it is summer but there you are dying of cold.
Y la última, porque en Argentina es verano pero ahí te estás muriendo de frío.
他们吃什么？
What do they eat?
¿Qué comen?
烤肉、小吃还是再加一点沙拉？
Roast or bitel toné or a little more salad?
¿Asado o bitel toné o un poco más de ensalada?
是的，事实是这里很新鲜，很新鲜，但是，是的，显然我要去吃烧烤。
Yes, the truth is that it is fresh here, it is fresh, but yes, obviously I am going to eat a barbecue.
Sí, la verdad que acá está fresco, está fresco, pero sí, obviamente voy a comer un asadito.
嗯，非常感谢恩佐。
Well, thank you very much Enzo.
Bueno, muchas gracias Enzo.
一个拥抱。
A hug.
Un abrazo.
我代表西班牙超级联赛的主场 Telemundo Deportes 表示感谢。
Thanks on behalf of Telemundo Deportes, the home of the Premier League in Spanish.
Gracias a nombre del Telemundo Deportes, la casa de la Premier League en español.
我们始终了解您所做的事情并表示祝贺。
We are always aware of what you do and congratulations.
Estamos siempre pendientes de lo que haces y felicidades.
非常感谢，一个拥抱，祝你好运。
Thank you very much, a hug, good luck.
Muchísimas gracias, un abrazo, suerte.